

# CONTACT



G-9 1402, Nirala Greenshire, Sector 2 Greater Noida West 203207



+91 9540368880



sanjeevkhanna802@gmail. com

# **COURSES**

YCB EXAM IN YOGA September 2022

Morarji Desai National Institute of yoga

CERTIFICATE COURSE IN YOGA
INSTRUCTOR September 2022

Morarji Desai National Institute of yoga

FOUNDATION COURSE IN YOGA SCIENCE FOR WELLNESS May 2021

Morarji Desai National Institute of yoga

# **SKILLS**

Asan Techniques

Time Management

Meditation

Paranayam

Adapdability

leadership

**Breathing Techniques** 

Continuous Learning

# Sanjeev Khanna

### YOGA INSTRUCTOR

I am highly dedicated and passionate yoga instructor with 7 years of experience guiding people towards physical, mental, and spiritual well-being. Proficient in various yoga styles, including ashtanga, hatha and Power Yoga. My area of expertise is helping person with problem like back pain, neck, shoulder, Thyroid, BP, sugar etc. I am always Ready to inspire and empower people on their yoga journey.

## **EDUCATION**

# **GURU JAMBESHWAR UNIVERSITY**

Post Graduate Diploma in Advertising and Management

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **YOGA INSTRUCTOR**

2023-Present

Fitt Lounge Sector-1 Greater Noida U.P.

#### YOGA INSTRUCTOR

Feb-june 2023

Xtreme Fitness Sector-1 ECO Village-1 Market U.P.

- Led group yoga classes in various styles, including Hatha, ashtanga, and pranayam, for students.
- Created and implemented well-structured yoga sequences that focused on breath awareness, proper alignment, and mindfulness.

#### **YOGA INSTRUCTOR**

June 2021 - June 2022

Nirala Greenshire Society Greater Noida West U.P.

- conducted group yoga with clear verbal instructions, demonstrations, and hands-on adjustments to ensure participants understood and executed each asana with correct posture, alignment, and breath control.
- Designed and facilitated an additional 15-day yoga camp, immersing participants in a transformative journey of selfdiscovery and well-being.

#### YOGA INSTRUCTOR

June 2016- May 2022

Shipra Sun City Indirapuram Ghaziabad U.P.

- Conducted one-on-one group yoga and created a supportive and inclusive environment, fostering a sense of community and personal growth among class participants
- Guided through meditation and mindfulness practices to promote mental and emotional well-being